A Guide to the Warren Weaver papers FA419
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Reprints, 1920-1987; 1933-1977; 12; 6 Cubic Feet
  - Works by Others, 2
    - Works by Others, undated (Box 63, Folder 521)
      - Piel, Gerard: Scientific American: Federal Funding of Science and the Autonomy of American Universities: A Constitutional Paradox (Box 63, Folder 521)
      - United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare: Alcohol and Alcoholism (Box 63, Folder 521)
      - Shannon, C.E. and J. McCarthy: Automata Studies (Box 63, Folder 521)
      - Tribus, Myron: Teaching Statistical Mechanics to Third-Year Students (Box 63, Folder 521)
      - Tribus, Myron: An Examination of Information Theory (Box 63, Folder 521)
    - Works by Others (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - Neugenbauer, O.: Journal of Near Eastern Studies: The History of Ancient Astronomy Problems and Methods, 1945 January (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - Report of the Committee of Consultants on Medical Research to the Subcommittee on Department of Labor and Health, Education, and Welfare of the Committee on Appropriations United States Senate. United States Government Printing Office: Federal Support of Medical Research, 1960 May (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - Wheeler, John A.: Geometrodynamics: Curved Empty Space-Time as the Building Material of the Physical World: An Assessment, 1961 March 3 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - American Institute of Physics: Glossary of Terms Frequently Used in High Energy Phyiscs, 1961 May 19 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - American Institute of Physics: Glossary of Terms Frequently Used in Cryogenics, 1962 August 13 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - American Institute of Physics: Glossary of Terms Frequently Used in Protein Chemistry, 1962 August 14 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - American Institute of Physics: Glossary of Terms Frequently Used in Biology of Nucleic Acids, 1962 August 15 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - American Institute of Physics: Glossary of Terms Frequently Used in Scientific Documentation, 1962 August 16 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - American Institute of Physics: Glossary of Terms Frequently Used in Physics of Oceanography, 1962 November 20 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - American Institute of Physics: Glossary of Terms Frequently Used in Space Physics, 1963 January 22 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - American Institute of Physics: Glossary of Terms Frequently Used in Biophyiscs, 1963 April 26 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - American Institute of Physics: Glossary of Terms Frequently Used Concerning Lasers, 1964 May 5 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - American Institute of Physics: Glossary of Terms Frequently Used in Quantum Mechanics, 1964 October 6 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - National Academy of Sciences: Physics: Survey and Outlook, 1966 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - American Institute of Physics: Glossary of Terms Frequently Used in Relativistic Astrophysics, 1967 January 28 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - Holland, James F.: Journal of the American Medical Association: The Kerbiozen Story: Is Cancer Quackery Dead?, 1967 April 17 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - American Institute of Physics: Glossary of Terms Frequently Used Concerning Noise Pollution, 1967 April 18 (Box 64, Folder 522)
      - Scientist and Citizen, 1968 December (Box 64, Folder 522)
- Warren Weaver Photographs and Special Formats, 1926-1970s; 13; 10253 Item(s) 35mm kodachrome slides, silver gelatin prints, color prints, nitrate sheet film negatives, 35mm nitrate and acetate roll film negatives, and 35mm color negatives. The total number of items in all formats for this collection is 10,253.
  Family photographs, Photographs taken during numerous trips to foreign countries, Landscape/Botanical interests, Group and individual portraits of the American Association of Mathematicians, dating from 1926 to the mid 1930's, and Publicity photographs of Warren Weaver.
  The family photographs date predominantly from the early 1920's through the 1950's, and are mostly of the Weaver children at various ages, family groups, holidays, graduations, weddings, vacations, and the construction of their house at Second Hill in the 1950's. WW seems to have had a particular interest in landscapes, and flower gardens.
  A large amount of the images dating from the mid 1960's to the late 1970's focus on nature scenes, gardens, and roses in particular. There is a vast amount of material taken during trips to Europe, Mexico, and Asia, dating from the late 1930's through 1968.
  Subjects of these images include architecture, historic landmarks, landscapes, cityscapes, and genre scenes.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  RAC Accession 2001:015.
  Photographic negatives cannot be handled or viewed by researchers due to the fragile nature of the format. To request duplication of an image(s), please contact an Archivist.
  Other Finding Aids
  A container list for this series is available as a PDF.
  Related Materials
  Rockefeller Foundation photographs, Series 100 Portraits.
  Photographs